enneagraminstitute.com 2018-12-30

# Privacy Policy — The Enneagram Institute

**The Enneagram Institute** ®  
 **Privacy Policy**  

This notice describes the Privacy Policy of Enneagram Personality Types, Inc., also known as The Enneagram Institute (“EI”). By using any services provided by the EI, such as using the EI website, purchasing test codes, taking a test offered by the EI (such as the RHETI and IVQ), creating and/or using an online account with EI, participating in training programs offered by EI, and/or agreeing to send or receive electronic communications to/from the EI (collectively, “Services”) you are accepting the terms described in this Privacy Policy, as they may be modified from time to time.  

Your use of our Services is also directed by our Terms of Use. If, after reviewing the Terms of Use and Privacy Policy, you have any questions or concerns, please contact us by email at support@enneagraminstitute.com.

 **Data Collection**

We do not collect personally identifiable information unless you voluntarily and knowingly provide it to us. When you voluntarily provide it, the information you provide is stored until we delete it in accordance with our regular business practices, or until you request that we delete your information. Data that we collect is stored on secure servers in the United States.

 **Collection of Personal Information**

If you create a Business Account on our website, you will create user credentials such as a user ID and password.  All passwords are encrypted before being stored in our database and passwords cannot be viewed by the EI. Therefore, if you forget your password, we are unable to send it to you via e-mail or provide it to you by any means. If you do forget your password, there is a ‘password reset’ option on the website that will allow you to reset your password.  

If you purchase any products or services through the website, including, but not limited to, purchasing test codes, your purchase will be processed through a secure third party payment processing system. EI does not have access to, or store, any of your payment or financial information, including credit card numbers. 

If you take a test offered by EI, such as the RHETI or IVQ, you will do so using a test code that you have purchased directly from the EI, or has been provided to you by the administrator of a Business Account or another third party. Your test results will only be sent to you if you are an individual test taker, or sent to you and/or a Business Account administrator if you use a test code provided by an organization having a Business Account. EI will not share your test results with anyone else. Your test results are stored on our secure servers until we delete them in accordance with our regular business practices, or until you request that we delete your information. 

If you use our website to take any tests, such as the RHETI or IVQ, we collect data via certain test questions/responses that will assist us in conducting research (“Research Data”). Research Data will be used only in aggregate form and does not include any personally-identifiable information.

 **Technical Information**

When you use our website, EI automatically receives and records technical information on our server logs from your browser or mobile platform, including your location, IP address, and cookie information.  An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computing device when you use the Internet. Cookies are alphanumerical identifiers that are transferred to your computing device’s hard drive through your web browser or mobile platform. Cookies allow our systems to identify the computing device and your browser. IP addresses may be used to help diagnose problems with our server, administer the website, analyze trends, track users' movement, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in order for us to improve the website, and deliver customized, personalized content.  We also use cookies to support our shopping cart. We reserve the right to use cookies and analyze web logs in accordance with our [Cookie Policy](http://www.enneagraminstitute.com/cookie-policy). 

We may also use third-party services and tools such as Google Analytics, which may provide EI with other information about your use of the website, but cannot be used to personally identify you.  These tools help us to understand traffic patterns and ascertain if there are problems with, or opportunities to improve, the website.  We treat this data as non-personal information, except where we are required to do otherwise under applicable law. Unless otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy, EI only uses this data in aggregate form.

 **Using Personal and/or Technical Information**

EI uses your personal information only for the purpose of providing Services to you and to communicate with you concerning The Enneagram Institute. We do not give or sell your personal information to advertisers or any other third parties. EI uses your technical information to personalize and improve the delivery of our Services, and to promote safety, integrity, and security in the use of our Services. 

**Limited Right to Share Personal Information**

EI shall have the limited right to share the personal information you provide: (1) to comply with valid legal requirements such as a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena or court order; or (2) in special cases, such as in response to a physical threat to you or others, to protect property, or defend or assert legal rights. In the event that EI is legally compelled to disclose your personal information to a third party, we will attempt to notify you unless doing so would violate the law or court order. 

**Sharing of Non-Personal Information**

EI shall have the right to share non-personal information, including aggregated information and data, with third parties. 

**Correcting or Erasing Your Personal Information**

In the event that any personal information you have provided to EI changes or is incorrect, you may request that we correct such information by notifying us via email at [support@enneagraminstitute.com](mailto:support@enneagraminstitute.com). Likewise, if you want your personal information to be erased from our records, you have the right for your personal information to be deleted from our active systems. Please send a request to [support@enneagraminstitute.com](mailto:support@enneagraminstitute.com). Your personal information will be deleted from our active systems within five (5) business days of receiving your request; however, your personal information will be retained on our backup systems until deleted in accordance with our regular backup retention practices. If we need to restore information from a backup to our active systems, we will delete your personal information from the records restored to our active systems.  

 **Protecting Children**

EI Services are not marketed or offered to, and not intended for, and should not be used by, any children under the age of 13. EI will not knowingly collect any information from individuals under the age of thirteen. By using our Services, you represent that you are over the age of 13 and old enough to consent to the processing of your personal data in your country, or that your parent or guardian gives consent on your behalf. If information is inadvertently collected for children under the age of 13, we will delete such information if we are notified or otherwise become aware of it. The Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) protects children under the age of thirteen from the online collection of personal information. Learn more about COPPA on the Federal Trade Commission’s website at www.ftc.gov. 

**Linking and Framing to Other Websites and Websites**

Our website and other EI electronic communications may display links and frames to other sites. Once you enter a third party website, or a portion of a third party site is framed within our website, you agree that EI is not responsible for the privacy practices of these other sites. EI encourages you to look for and review the privacy statements of each and every website that you visit.

EI makes no representation, warranty or endorsement, express or implied, as to any of the information, services, products or messages on any third party websites which may be accessed through the EI website. In particular, these links and frames are provided for convenience only and are not intended as an endorsement by EI of the organization or individual operating the website or a warranty or endorsement of any type regarding the website or the information, services, products or messages posted on or available from such website.

 **E-Communications from EI**

EI may send you emails or other electronic communications regarding the Enneagram Institute and/or its Services. These electronic communications will be sent to the email address that you provide to us. Should you wish to cease receiving these electronic communications, you can opt out via the instructions provided by EI.

EI will never send you an email requesting your password, credit card number, or social security number. If you receive a message that looks like it is from EI, but asks you for your password, credit card number, or social security number, it is a fraudulent email, or “phish”. We recommend you report it to the proper authorities.  

 **Questions or Comments**

If you have any questions or comments about the EI, its Services, or this Privacy Policy, please contact us:

The Enneagram Institute®  
3355 US Highway 209  
Stone Ridge, NY 12484  
Phone: (845) 687-9878  
Fax: (845) 687-7486  
support@enneagraminstitute.com ** **

 **Effective Date:**   September 24, 2018
